Select Page

Privacy Policy
==============

Blomp Privacy Policy

Posted: January 27, 2023

Effective: February 27, 2023

Thanks for using Blomp! Here we describe how we collect, use and handle your information when you use our websites, software and services (“Services”).

What & Why
----------

We collect and use the following information to provide, improve and protect our Services:

Account. We collect, and associate with your account, information like your name, email address, phone number, payment info,  and account activity. Some of our services let you access your accounts and your information with other service providers.

Services. Our Services are designed to make it simple for you to store Your Stuff, collaborate with others, and work across multiple devices. To make that possible, we store, process, and transmit Your Stuff—like files, messages, comments, and photos—as well as information related to it. This related information can be things like your profile information that makes it easier to collaborate and share Your Stuff with others. Our Services provide you with different options for sharing Your Stuff.

You may choose to give us access to your contacts to make it easy for you to do things like share and collaborate on Your Stuff, send messages, and invite others to use the Services. If you do, we’ll store those contacts on our servers for you to use.

Usage. We collect information related to how you use the Services, including actions you take in your account (like sharing, editing, viewing, and moving files or folders). This helps us provide you with features like the “Events” page and version history.

We also collect information from and about the devices you use to access the Services. This includes things like IP addresses, the type of browser and device you use, the web page you visited before coming to our sites, and identifiers associated with your devices. Your devices (depending on their settings) may also transmit location information to the Services.

Cookies and other technologies. We use technologies like cookies and pixel tags to provide, improve, protect and promote our Services. For example, cookies help us with things like remembering your username for your next visit, understanding how you are interacting with our Services, and improving them based on that information. You can set your browser to not accept cookies, but this may limit your ability to use the Services.

With whom
---------

We may share information as discussed below, but we won’t sell it to advertisers or other third parties.

Certain features (file sharing) let you make additional information available to others.

Other applications. You can also give third parties access to your information and account – for example, via Blomp APIs, Apple iCloud or others. Just remember that their use of your information will be governed by their privacy policies and terms.

Law & Order. We may disclose your information to third parties if we determine that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with the law; (b) protect any person from death or serious bodily injury; (c) prevent fraud or abuse of Blomp or our users; or (d) protect Blomp’s property rights.

Stewardship of your data is critical to us and a responsibility that we embrace. We believe that our users’ data should receive the same legal protections regardless of whether it’s stored on our services or on their home computer’s hard drive. We’ll abide by the following Government Request Principles when receiving, scrutinizing and responding to government requests (including national security requests) for our users’ data:

Be transparent,

Fight blanket requests,

Protect all users and

Provide trusted services.

We publish a Transparency Report as part of our commitment to informing users about when and how governments ask us for information. This report details the types and numbers of requests we receive from law enforcement. We encourage users to review our Government Request Principles and Transparency Report for more detailed information on our approach and response to government requests.

How
---

Security. We have a team dedicated to keeping your information secure and testing for vulnerabilities. We also continue to work on features to keep your information safe in addition to things like two-factor authentication, encryption of files at rest, and alerts when new devices and apps are linked to your account.

Retention. We’ll retain information you store on our Services for as long as we need it to provide you the Services. If you delete your account, we’ll also delete this information. But please note: (1) there might be some latency in deleting this information from our servers and back-up storage; and (2) we may retain this information if necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, or enforce our agreements. You can access your personal information by logging into your Blomp account. Learn more here.

Where
-----

Around the world. To provide you with the Services, we may store, process and transmit information in the United States and locations around the world – including those outside your country. Information may also be stored locally on the devices you use to access the Services.

EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield. When transferring data from the European Union, the European Economic Area, and Switzerland, Blomp relies upon a variety of legal mechanisms, including contracts with our users. Blomp complies with the EU-U.S. and Swiss–U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union, the European Economic Area, and Switzerland to the United States.  You can also learn more about Privacy Shield at [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

Blomp is subject to oversight by the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. JAMS is the US-based independent organization responsible for reviewing and resolving complaints about our Privacy Shield compliance — free of charge to you. We ask that you first submit any such complaints directly to us via [support@Blomp.com](mailto:support@blomp.com). If you aren’t satisfied with our response, please contact JAMS at [https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield](https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield). In the event your concern still isn’t addressed by JAMS, you may be entitled to a binding arbitration under Privacy Shield and its principles.

Changes
-------

If we are involved in a reorganization, merger, acquisition or sale of our assets, your information may be transferred as part of that deal. We will notify you (for example, via a message to the email address associated with your account) of any such deal and outline your choices in that event.

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time, and will post the most current version on our website. If a revision meaningfully reduces your rights, we will notify you.

Contact
-------

Have questions or concerns about Blomp, our Services and privacy? Contact us at [support@blomp.com](mailto:support@blomp.com).

----------------------------------------------------------------------

Blomp is your permanent home for all of your family memories and valuable files. Blomp is reliable, secure and best of all free!

Use Blomp through any of one of our apps to always have access to your music, movies and photos. Use your own software with our open standards interface and really surprise us. Blomp grows with you whether you need 20GB, 200GB, 2TB or more!

Blomp ©
